本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
梅宝  你相信世界上有鬼吗
Mabel, do you believe in ghosts?
我相信你是个大笨蛋  哈哈哈
I believe you're a big dork! Ha ha ha ha!
苏斯  温蒂
Soos! Wendy!
怎么了  派恩斯先生
What's up, Mr. Pines?
我要出去一趟  你们把浴室打扫一下  知道吗
I'm headin' out. You two are gonna wash the bathrooms, right?
-没问题  -没门
- Yes, sir. - Absolutely not.
你们别给我惹麻烦
You stay outta trouble.
嘿伙计们  瞧瞧这是什么
Hey, guys, what's this?
通向屋顶的秘密楼梯
A secret ladder to the roof?
呃  我觉得派恩斯先生不会允许你们这样的
Uh, I don't think Mr. Pines would like that.
你把我给吓着了  伙计
You're freakin' me out, dude!
我们真的可以上去吗
Can we actually go up there?
当然了  屋顶时间  屋顶时间
Sure we can. Roof time! Roof time!
屋顶时间  屋顶时间
Roof time! Roof time!
好啦  瞧瞧吧
All right, check it out.
哇 哇  酷毙了
Whoa! Whoa, cool!
你把这些东西弄上来的
You put all this stuff up here?
我偶尔抽空溜到上面来玩一下
I may or may not sneak up here during work,
每天都来  无时无刻不在这儿
All the time, every day.
耶
Yes!
- 好的  - 我先来
- All right. - Me first!
中奖了  来击掌吧
Jackpot! High five!
别让我苦等着哟
Don't leave me hangin'.
嘿  我朋友来了
Hey, it's my friends.
温蒂
Wendy!
呃  你们不会告诉斯坦的  对吧
Uh, you guys aren't gonna tell stan about this, are you?
回见啦  傻蛋儿们
Later, dorks.
咱们走吧
Let's get outta here!
回见  温蒂
Later, Wendy!
啊  好好玩
Ah, good times.
-干嘛啊  -有人恋爱喽
- What? - Somebody's in love!
得了吧
Yeah, right.
我只是觉得温蒂很酷啦
I just think wendy's cool, okay?
我又没有整晚想她想得睡不着觉
It's not like I lay awake at night thinking about her.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
翻译： 芭小豆
校订： WaitinZ
■
后期： WaitinZ  liloelva
怪诞小镇  第一季第五集
Gravity Falls  S01E05  The Inconveniencing
无缘由舞会开始啦
Put on some dance party for no reason!
跳  跳  跳
Go! Go! Go!
跳  跳  跳  跳  跳
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
我正在假装写点什么
-迪普  -什么  咋了  啥事儿
- Dipper! - What? Yes? Yeah?
你不来一起跳吗
Aren't you gonna get in on this?
我  呃  不太会跳舞
I, uh, don't really dance.
你明明会
Yeah, you do.
妈妈曾经给他穿了件羊羔服
Mom used to dress him up in a lamb costume
让他跳
And make him do...
羊羔舞
The lamby dance.
现在不是讨论羊羔舞的时候啦
Now is not the time to talk about the lamby dance.
羊羔服  哇
Lamb costume? Whoa!
是不是有耳朵有尾巴的那种
Is there, like, little ears and a tail, or...?
这个嘛  呃 呃
Well, uh... Uh...
迪普一边蹦Q一边唱关于吃草的歌
Dipper would prance around and sing a song about grazing.
嘿  瞧啊
Hey, look at that.
下班喽  朋友们等着我呢
Quittin' time. The gang's waitin' for me.
嘿  等等  呃  我可以一起
Hey, wait, uh, maybe I could--
我是说我们可以一起去吗
Or could come with you.
噢  这个不清楚哎
Ooh, I don't know.
我的朋友们都有点癫狂
My friends are pretty intense.
你们说你们多大来着
How old did you guys say you are?
我们十三了  严格来说算得上是青少年咯
We're 13, so, technically a teen.
好吧  勇气可嘉哦  小孩儿
All right. I like your moxie, kid.
我去拿下东西
Let me get my stuff.
我们咋就十三了呢  难道今年是闰年
Since when are we 13? Is this a leap year?
想想看  梅宝  这是个难得的机会
Come on, mabel. This is our chance to hang out with,
可以跟那些酷毙了的小孩儿们一起玩儿  还有温蒂
You know, the cool kids-- and Wendy and whatever.
我就知道  你爱上她啦
I knew it! You love her!
爱她  爱她  爱她  爱她  爱她
Love, love, love, love, love!
噢  看那是什么
Oh, hey, what's that?
快点啦
Hurry up.
打肚脐  打肚脐
In the belly! In the belly!
温蒂
Wendy!
温蒂  温蒂
Wendy! Wendy!
嘿  大家伙儿  这是我的工友们  梅宝和迪普
Hey, guys, these are my pals from work, mabel and dipper.
我把口香糖嚼成大脑的形状了哟
I chewed my gum so it looks like a brain.
她一般给人的第一印象都不太好
She's not much for first impressions,
就不像我
Unlike this guy!
我哦
This guy...!
所以你是在  做保姆吗还是
So are you, like, babysitting or...?
不是啦  罗比
Come on, Robbie.
这是李跟内特
Guys, this is Lee and Nate...
谭布丽
Tambri...
汤普森  曾经花五毛钱吃了一个被碾过的华夫饼
Thompson, who once ate a run-over waffle for 50 cents...
这个就别跟他们说了吧
Don't tell them that.
这是罗比  你们可能已经知道他了
And Robbie. You can probably figure him out.
没错  水塔上的涂鸦就是我画的
Yeah, I'm the guy who spray-painted the water tower.
就那个大蛋糕形状的涂鸦吗
Oh, you mean the big muffin.
呃  是个大爆炸的形状
Um, it's a giant explosion.
哈哈  确实有点像蛋糕
Heh heh! Kind of does look like a muffin.
快点走啦  伙计们  今晚咱还有大计划呐
Let's hurry it up, guys. I got big plans for tonight, huh?
快走吧  上车
Let's get outta here! Get in the car!
不好意思  毛孩儿  前排我已经占了
Sorry, kid, I'll ride shotgun, all right?
好了  走之前我必须得说
Okay, just, before we go,
我妈说不让你们打车顶了  所以
My mom said you guys aren't allowed to punch the roof anymore, so...
汤普森  汤普森  汤普森
Thompson! Thompson! Thompson!
你今天看起来很漂亮！
哈哈  这样会给某人留下深刻印象哦
Ha ha! This is gonna blow someone's mind.
梅宝  拜托啦
Mabel, please.
咋了  嫌我给你丢人了
What? Am I embarrassing you in front of your new...
在你女朋友面前
Girlfriend!
啊  你舔我手干嘛
Uhh! Did you just lick my hand?
您正在收看的是
You're watching the black-and-white
黑白无聊老妪电影频道
Period piece old lady boring movie channel.
孩子们  遥控器在哪儿  我不想起身
Kids! I can't find the remote, and I refuse to stand up!
周五晚间影片播映室即将为您播映电影《女爵的应允》
Stay tuned for the Friday night movie, The Duchess Approves,
由斯特莉・斯坦伯博尔吉斯饰演女爵
Starring Sturly Stembleburgiss as the Duchess
格兰普顿・圣・拉普特弗拉伯饰演可笑的舵手
And Grampton St. Rumpterfrabble as the risible coxswain
桑特尔布拉格特・汉普特法宾塞尔
Sounterbluggot Hampterfuppinshire.
孩子们
Kids!
女爵的应允
礼服由佩比提供
不  不
No! Noooo!
伙计们  我们到了
There it is, fellas--
废弃的  黄昏到黎明便利店
The condemned Dusk-to-Dawn.
-酷  -太棒了
- Neato! - Awesome!
为什么废弃了呢
Wh-why did they shut it down?
是因为违反了卫生规定之类的吗
It's, like, a health code violation, or...?
-是谋杀  -有人死在里面了
- Try murder! - Some folks died in there.
自那以后这里常常闹鬼哦
The place has been haunted ever since.
这个小镇的历史真实丰富多彩
This town has such a colorful history!
什么  你们是认真的么
What? Are-- are you guys serious?
当然了  我们马上就要死了
Yeah. We're all gonna die!
别怕嘛  没有看上去那么糟啦
Chill out, man. It's not as bad as it looks.
禁止翻越  违者必死
下来啊  迪普
Come on, Dipper.
哈哈  好  好啊
Haha, Okay. Okay
等我踩稳了的
Just-- just gotta get a foothold.
哥们儿  你姐姐都行
Dude, your sister did it.
嘿  你知道吗  这样就行了
Hey, you know what? Just... There you go.
对不起  哥们儿
Sorry, dude.
把小孩儿直接扔下围栏  真是天才
Good job throwing the kid off the fence, genius.
你妈才是天才
Your mom's a genius.
这地方真不赖啊
This place is amazing.
我觉得好像  锁上了
I think it's-- it's stuck.
-我来试试  -哦  行啊
- Let me take a crack at it. - Oh, yeah.
我反正进不去  但是我相信这个
I can't get in, but I'm sure junior here
小毛孩子能像大力士一样把门弄开
Is gonna break it down like hercules.
行了  少说两句  干嘛非得跟小孩过不去呢
Come on, leave him alone. He's just a little kid.
哇  小孩儿  你要干什么啊
Whoa, kid! What are you doing?
加油  迪普  把那个金属玩意儿打成稀巴烂
Go, dipper! Punch that metal thing!
嘿  迪普  冷静点啊
Hey, dipper, take it easy.
谁想赌他失败
Who wants to bet he doesn't make it?
干得不错  小疯孩儿
Good call, inviting this little maniac!
从现在起叫你欢乐时光博士好了
Your new name is Dr. Fun Times.
不错
All right.
帅呆啦  哥们儿
Yeah, man. Cool.
干得不错
Nice work.
你们真相信这里闹鬼吗
Do you guys really think it's haunted?
汤普森  开什么玩笑
Thompson, are you kidding me?
得了吧  闭嘴吧  老兄
Come on, shut up, man!
没错，我们正在营业
快走吧！我们已经打烊
噢  天哪
Oh, man.
比我想象的还要毛骨悚然一点
It's even creepier than I imagined.
尘土  鉴定完毕
Yep, it's dust.
嘿  哥们儿  你说尸体被藏在哪了呢
Hey, dude, where do you think they keep the dead bodies?
闭嘴啦
Shut up, man!
兄弟们 你们觉得这开关还能用吗
Guys, check it out! You think they still work?
真棒
Nice!
帅呆了
Jackpot!
那么现在我们要做什么呢
So, what are we gonna do now?
想做什么都可以啊
Anything we want.
尝尝这个吧
Take that.
放进去  放进去  一次放仨  一次放仨
Put 'em in, put 'em in! Three at a time, three at a time!
噢天哪  笑笑糖
Oh, my gosh! Smile dip!
我还以为这玩意儿国内被禁售了呢
I thought this stuff was banned in America.
不卖是有原因的
Maybe they had a good reason.
哥们儿  我们准备好了  快过来
Hey, come here, man, we got it ready!
不管是啥  我都玩定了
Whatever it is, I'll do it!
汤普森
Thompson!
迪普  今晚太嗨了  会成为传奇载入史册的
Dipper, this night is, like, legendary.
-真的吗  -你看啊  弟兄们玩得多开心
- Really? - Just look around. The guys are bonding.
我从来没见过谭布丽眼睛离开手机这么久的时间
I've never even seen tambri look up from her phone this long,
而你姐姐看来已经吃笑笑糖吃疯了
And your sister seems to be going nuts for that smile dip.
我可能吃得太多了
Maybe I've had too much.
你觉得呢
What you think?
想尝尝我的糖爪子吗
Would you like to eat my candy paws?
当然想啦  你真是个天使
Of course, you little angel.
知道吗  迪普  我之前不太确定
You know, dipper, I wasn't sure
你能不能融合进我们这个圈子
If you could hang with our crew at first,
不过看起来你真的是比你同龄的人要成熟许多
But you're surprisingly mature for your age.
是的没错  太对了
Yes. Yes, I am.
嘿  哥们儿  再给来点儿冰
Hey, guys, We need more ice.
我去拿
I'm on it.
怎么了
What was that?
我好像听到姑娘的尖叫声了哦
I thought I heard some lady screaming back here.
毛孩儿  你吓坏了吧
You freakin' out, kid?
没  没啊  我没事儿  挺好的
No. No, I'm cool. Everything's cool.
没事儿怎么会成这样
Then what's all this about?
哦  这是  那个  呃 呃
Oh, that's... Uh... Uh... Uh...
嘿 瞧
Hey, look!
跳舞机
Dancy pants revolution,
可以达到健身目的游戏机
The game that tricks people into exercising.
走了  去看看
All right, I'm down.
耶  我们去玩吧  去玩吧
Yeah, let's all-- let's all go play that.
舞起来吧  快点哦
Dance! Hurry up!
加油  加油  加油
Go! Go! Go! Go!
哇  他真是逊死了
Wow! He's really terrible at this.
是  是啊  还行吧  不错
Yeah, yeah, that's-- that's great.
我一会儿就回来
I'll be right back.
快点啊  斯坦叔公  接电话啊
Come on, Grunkle Stan, pick up!
他到底在干些什么
Uhh! What is he doing?
我才不在乎他是公爵  是平民
I don't care about dukes or commoners...
还是康沃尔莱诺阁下
Or his royal highness, Lionel of Cornwall.
母亲大人  我不再惧怕了
I'm not afraid anymore, mother.
女爵  我不允许你这样
Duchess, I forbid you.
我是女爵  可我也是个女人
I may be a duchess, but I'm also a woman!
对啊  对啊
Yes! Yes!
去你的  伊丽莎白
In your face, elizabeth!
我们同病相怜啊
It's just like my life!
某种程度上吧
In a way.
梅宝  我们得想想办法
Mabel, I need your advice.
我们在一个闹鬼的便利店里玩
We're hanging out in a haunted convenience store,
我又联系不上斯坦叔公
I can't get ahold of Grunkle Stan,
要是跟他们说这事儿的话
And if I try to say anything about it to any of these guys,
他们会觉得我是胆小的小毛孩子
they'll just think I'm a scared little kid or something.
梅宝
Mabel?
未来已成为过去
The future is in the past!
前进  鲨鱼怪
Onward, deoshebah!
梅宝  你到底吃了多少这玩意儿
Mabel! How many of these did you eat?
习一袋咧
Eleventeen.
天啊  地啊  娘啊
Oh, man. Oh man, oh man, oh man!
哇  伙计们  来看看这个
Whoa, guys, you might wanna see this.
真见鬼
What the heck?
哇  看来传言是真的
Whoa. Then the rumors are true.
哥们儿  你敢躺进去吗
Dude, dare you to lie down in it.
好主意  躺进去吧
Good idea. Go lie down in it.
我是尸体  瞧好
I'm a dead body! Look!
等一下
Wait!
我们还是不要这么做了吧
Maybe let's not do that.
他害怕了哟
This guy's  scared!
我想说的是  为什么要冒这种险呢
All I'm saying is, why tempt the fates?
我是说万一这个便利店真的
I mean, what if this place really is...
有鬼呢
Haunted?
-拜托  -切
- Come on. -Boo.
能不能冷静一点  泼冷水先生
Just take it down a notch, Captain Buzzkill.
我不是欢乐时光博士么
But I thought I was Dr. Fun times.
呃  你表现得确实有点像泼冷水先生  你不觉得吗
Well, you're acting like Captain Buzzkill, right?
是啊  确实有一点
Yeah. Little bit.
发个状态
Status update:
与九岁疯童一起被困便利店
Trapped in store with insane 9-year-old.
我不是九岁  我十三了
I'm not a 9-year-old. I'm 13,
是严格意义上的青少年了
Technically a teen!
哇  怎么回事
Whoa? What is that?
什么
What?
更新状态
"status update...
啊啊啊啊啊啊
Aaaahhhhhhh."
谭布丽  谭布丽
Tambri! Tambri!
你能听到我们吗
Can you hear us?
-我们该怎么办  -我不知道啊哥们儿  不知道啊
What are we supposed to do? I don't know, man! I don't know!
我们赶紧逃出去吧
Let's just go already!
-汤普森  -等一下
- Thompson! - Wait!
我马上就得最高分了
I've almost got the high score!
怎么
What?
快把你的看家本领拿出来吧
Time to shake what your momma gave you!
哦不  救命啊  好多箭头啊
Oh, no! Help! So many arrows!
你是个跳舞的机器
You're a dance machine!
不  你才是跳舞的机器
No, you're a dance machine!
-哦不  -汤普森
- Oh, no! - Thompson!
别管他了  赶紧逃吧
Forget him! Let's go!
大爷的  伙计们  门锁上了
What the--? Guys, it's locked!
休想挡爷的路
Outta my way!
大家冷静一下
Everybody, wait.
不管发生了什么肯定是有原因的
Whatever is doing this has to have some kind of reason.
也许我们能搞清楚到底是怎么回事儿
Maybe if we could just figure out what it is,
然后就能出去了
Then they'll let us out of here.
"然后就能出去了"
"they'll let us out of here."
对啊  真的能解决掉问题哎
Yeah, that makes a lot of sense.
我也不确定  但是伙计们  他说的也许有道理啊
I don't know, guys. Maybe he's got a point.
对啊  没错
Yeah, right.
我觉得鬼怪们只是想说出他们的感受罢了
I'm sure the ghost just wants to talk about his feelings!
什 什么
Wh-what?
我要活吃了你
I'm bonkers for eating you alive!
不
No!
李
Lee!
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
我支持你  百分百支持你  哥们儿
I'm with you, kid. One hundred percent, man.
欢迎你们
Welcome!
他们控制了梅宝
They got mabel!
欢迎来到你们的葬身之地  不懂事儿的擅闯者们
Welcome to your graves, young trespassers!
真抱歉在你们的店里逗留
We're super sorry for hanging out in your store.
是啊  我们现在就离开永远也不再来了
Yeah, can we just go now and leave forever?
呃  好吧  你们可以走了
Well... Okay. You're free to go.
不过在你们走之前  热狗肠马上就好了
But before you leave, hot dogs are now half off.
我知道这听起来有点疯狂  不过  你们吃了再走吧
I know it might be crazy, but you gotta try these dogs!
我就是开个卖热狗肠的玩笑
Just kidding about the hot dog sale!
赶紧让我们出去
Just let us outta here already!
我不喜欢你的语气
I don't like your tone!
不 不  啊
No, no! Aah!
什么  不  我变成热狗肠啦
What? No! I'm a hot dog!
好戏开始了
It begins!
欢迎来到你们永远的归宿
Welcome to your home for all eternity!
-迪普  我们该怎么办  -低头
Dipper, what do we do? Duck!
快  躲进那里
Quick, in there!
他们想从我们这得到什么呢
What do they want from us?
-他们想报仇吧  我猜  -我们做错了什么
- Revenge, I guess...? - What did we do wrong?
好吧  我们分析一下现在的情况
Okay, let's try to figure out the pattern here.
他们分别为什么被困住呢
Why was each person taken?
谭布丽在发短信  汤普森在打电玩
Tambri was texting, thompson was playing a video game,
李说话爱讽刺  但是这说不通啊
Lee was being sarcastic-- it doesn't make any sense!
是啊  的确  这些事情是普通青少年常做的事啊
Yeah. I mean, those are all just normal teenage things.
温蒂  最后一句重复一遍
Wendy, say that last part again.
“青少年常做的事”
"Normal teenage things"?
我明白啦  别出去等我回来
Of course! Stay here until I get back.
嘿  哥们儿  你要干嘛
Dude, what are you doing?
嘿  鬼
Hey, ghost!
我有件事要告诉你
I've got something to tell you.
我不是青少年
I'm not a teenager!
呃  你为什么刚才不说呢
Well, why didn't you say so?
那你几岁啊
How old did you say you were?
我
I'm...
我十二岁  严格来讲不是青少年
I'm 12, technically not a teen.
我们还活着的时候  青少年们简直就是我们店里的祸害
When we were alive, teenagers were a scourge on our store.
总是带着震天响的音响
Always sassafrassin' customers
穿着怪异不整的裤子
With their boomie-boxes
骚扰我们的顾客
And disrespectful short pants,
所以我们决定禁止他们入内
So we decided to up and ban them,
但是他们用新奇的说唱音乐进行报复
But they retaliated with this newfangled rap music!
歌词简直太讨厌了
The lyrics, they were so... Hateful!
作业和规则一样疯狂
Homework's wack, and so are rules
把衣服掖进去才荒唐
Tuckin' in your shirt's for fools
不
Nooo!
太令人厌恶了  它把我们折磨到
It was so shocking,   we were stricken down
双双心脏病发
With double heart attacks.
这就是为什么我们这么讨厌青少年
That's why we hate teenagers so much,
对吧  亲爱的
Don't we, honey?
但是他们是我的好朋友啊
But they're my friends.
就没有什么方法救他们了吗
Isn't there anything I can do to help them?
的确有一个方法
There is one thing.
你会不会跳搞笑的舞蹈
Do you know any funny little dances?
呃  我有没有别的选择呢
Uh... Is there anything else I can do?
没有
Nooooo!
好吧  好吧  嗯
Okay, okay, okay! Um, well...
我确实会跳羊羔舞啦
I do know... The lamby-lamby dance,
但是  没有羊羔服不能跳啊
But, uh, but I can't really do it without a lamb costume.
哦  呃  这样就可以了
Oh. Well. There it is.
好
Well
谁想要一只小羊羔
Who wants a lamby, lamby, lamby?
我要  我要
I do! I do!
那就快去跟你的妈妈打个招呼
So go up and greet your mammy mammy mammy
你好  你好
Hi there, hi there
然后就在雏菊周围走  走  走
So march, march, march around the daisies
好 好 再来再来
Yes! Yes! More, more!
千万千万千万别忘了你的宝贝
don't, don't, don't you forget about the baby
真是太好了  女孩子气的跳舞男孩
That was some fine girlie-dancin', boy!
你的朋友们自由了
Your friends are free.
呃  我想你们不用担心我们会再来了
Well, I don't think you have to worry about us comin' back, so...
我以后什么也不吃了  啥也不干了
I'm never gonna eat or  do  anything ever again.
-嘿  这儿还剩了一点  -坏人
- Hey, there's still some left. - Evil!
我们出事后发生了什么
What-- what happened after everything went crazy?
你们绝对不会相信
You are not going to believe it.
鬼们显形了  而迪普
The ghosts appeared, and dipper had to...
迪普抄着根棍子
And, um, dipper just grabbed a bat
给鬼们一顿爆揍  左右开弓
And started beating ghosts down, left and right.
给两个鬼吓坏了
And then the ghosts got all scared
落荒而逃  跟俩小姑娘似的
And ran away like a couple of little girls.
-太疯狂了  -不会吧
- It was insane! - No way!
欢乐时光博士
Dr. Fun Times!
呃  这事儿我一辈子都忘不了
Well, I'm probably scarred for life.
是啊  确实挺疯狂的
Yeah, that was pretty crazy.
我得面壁好好琢磨琢磨这事儿的经过
Think I'm gonna go stare at a wall for a while and rethink everything.
嘿  下次一起玩的话
Hey, next time we hang out,
我们还是呆在神秘小屋吧
Let's stay at the Mystery Shack, okay?
哈 哈  下一次
Ha ha! Next time?
好啊  就 就在小屋里玩吧
Yeah, let's-- let's hang out at the shack.
哈 哈  好啊
Ha ha! Yeah.
下一次
Next time.
这什么破笑话啊  真恶心
What kind of sick joke is this?
婚礼到了
The wedding.
让我等得太辛苦了
I've waited so long for this.
哦  瞧啊  她穿婚纱多漂亮
Oh, look at her in that dress.
莱诺伯爵  他来干什么
Count Lionel! What's he doin' here?!
我来抢回我的新娘
I've come to reclaim my bride!
刚才跳交谊舞的时候你本来是有机会的
You had your chance at the cotillion, you!
那是我刚才说的
That's what I'm sayin'!
找不到遥控器了
Couldn't find the remote.